本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流之用 更多中日双语字幕，请登录 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:mam  校对: maize　时间轴：那年夏天  后期：娜夏
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
高校のころ 伊禮がサーフィンやってるのを
よく こうして見に来てたよ
I came to watch Irei surfing here back in high school.
八汐みたいに 部活サボってな
ミッチーって アキちゃんより駄目部長だったんじゃない？
I skipped my club activities too.
よく言われたさ 伊禮にも 瀬乃宮にも
You were an even worse club president than Aki, weren't you?
I was told that quite often. By Irei and Senomiya too.
瀬乃宮からな 弔電が届いたってよ
あぁ ここで言うのは 姉の方な
Senomiya sent a message with her condolences.
The older sister, I mean.
瑞榎さんは ミサ姉に「ありがとう」って…
Mizuka told me to say thanks to Misa...
伊禮はな とんでもねえ酒豪だったんだぞ
これ 豆知識な
Irei always was a heavy drinker.
献杯だ
Just saying.
Here's to her.
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
Everything scatters, leaving void
真理のために今ここにいるよ
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
The stage with our careless justice
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
The Robotics Research Club is disbanded as of today!
単刀直入に言いますが
Let me put this straight.
The Robotics Research Club is disbanded as of today.
ロボット研究部は 今日をもって廃部とします
But... I'm taking the blame for being negligent...
そんな
今回のことは 自分の監督不行き届きでもありますし…
日高君のお父さまが大変お怒りなのです
Hidaka's father is furious.
分かりますね
I hope you understand.
Yes.
はい
ＪＡＸＡさんとの提携についても これ以上のご協力は頂けません
We cannot allow any further
cooperation with JAXA either.
私どもとしましても 安全管理に不備がなかったか深く反省しています
We are reflecting on whether there were any problems regarding safety.
支援事業についても継続できないと 上から言われました
The higher-ups ordered us to cease all support too.
当然 万博への出展も取りやめです
Of course the same goes for the Expo entry as well.
スペースアメ社さんも それで問題ありませんね
The Space Candy company has no problems with that either?
残念じゃが 仕方ないのう
It's unfortunate, but there is nothing we can do now.
ロボット研究部で製作したロボットも 全て解体します
You are to destroy every robot you built in your club.
いいですね
Yes.
はい
面談の後 病院へ行った
After the meeting, we went to the hospital,
Tanegashima Public Hospital
だが 昴に会うことはできなかった
but we couldn't see Subaru.
His father told the hospital not to let us meet him.
父親が俺たちを会わせないようにと 病院側に話していたからだ
Subaru's wounds are grave, and he might never be the same again.
昴のケガは重く 後遺症が残る可能性もあるとのことだった
それとは別に ジュンちゃんは昴の家に謝りに行って…
Also, Jun went to his place to apologize.
あんたのせいじゃないのは分かってる
I know it wasn't your fault.
分かってはいるが もう息子とは関わらんでくれ
I know that, but still, stay away from my son.
He sounded really... lonely.
すごく さみしそうだった
That doesn't change that it was my fault.
私のせいっていうのは何も変わらないのに
I can't forgive myself...
私は 私のこと 許せないのに
It wasn't your fault, Jun. Don't dwell on it so much.
あれはジュンのせいじゃない そんなに思い詰めないで
I'm sorry, Akiho, Yashio.
ごめんね あき穂ちゃん 八汐君
危ない
Watch out!
全部 私のせいだから
It was all my fault...
If only... If only I quit the club and—
私… 私がロボ部を辞めて…
That's pointless, Jun.
それ 無意味だよ ジュンちゃん
ロボ部は もう なくなったから
The club's no more.
Kai, are you an idiot?!
バカ カイ
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい
Kona
電話 つないで
Pick it up.
Kona
ども ひ… 久しぶり
Hello. I-It's been a while.
Are you okay, Kona?
こなちゃんは大丈夫？
I'm fixing the autobalancer.
オートバランサー 調整中
In part, it happened because my program was still imperfect.
す… すかすかガンヴァレルが倒れたのは
私のプログラムが未熟だったからでもあるし
So I'm feeding back the data I gathered these few days so that—
だ… だから ここ何日かで得たデータ フィードバックして…
The Robotics Club got disbanded.
ロボ部は廃部になった
ロボも解体される
The robots will get taken apart too.
そ… そういうことは もっと早く言ってほしかったわけだが
Y-You should've told me earlier...
I had a lot on my plate too.
こっちも いっぱい いっぱいでね
どうしたの
What's wrong?
や… 八汐先輩
Yashio,
な… 何か 怖くね？
isn't this scary?
怖い？
Scary?
せ… 先輩 言ってたよね
You said that Kagome-Kagome played before her Powered Suit went out of control.
パワードスーツが暴走する前に『かごめかごめ』が流れたって
そ… それって やっぱり君島レポートと何か関係があるんじゃ…
Does that mean there's some connection with the Kimijima Reports?
I told you not to stick your nose in stuff that's not your business.
言ったろ 余計なことに首 突っ込むんじゃないって
Stop digging any further.
この辺で 手を引いときな
足を… こいつをプレゼントしてくれてありがとうって…
Yashio...
Tell her thanks for this.
俺に対する警告とか？
A warning to me?
そ… そこまでは分からないけど
I wouldn't say that...
ご… ごめん
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
いや 悪い 疲れてるから切るね
Sorry, I'm really tired.
Bye.
じゃあ
Call Ended
ダウンロードしますか
Do you wish to download?
八汐海翔
Yashio Kaito.
エグゾスケルトン社の澤田だ
I am Sawada from Exoskeleton, Inc.
パワードスーツが暴走したときのことを聞きたい
I want to ask you about how the Powered Suit went out of control.
な… 何ですか
What? I told the police everything I know already.
知ってることは全部 警察に話しました
Yes, I know.
ああ 聞いている
暴走したとき 不思議な音が鳴ったようだが
You said it emitted a weird noise when it went out of control.
その音に 心当たりは？
Did you know that sound?
例えば 他の場所で聞いたとか
For example, had you heard it somewhere else?
Unknown
いえ…
No...
I see.
そうか
では 君島コウという人物に心当たりは？
Then are you familiar with the name Kimijima Kou?
No...
いいえ…
君島コウは 愛理という少女と関わりがあった
Kimijima Kou was close to the girl named Airi.
君は コールドスリープ状態の愛理の発見者だそうだが
You are the one who found Airi in a cold sleep.
I just found her.
見つけただけです
そうか
I see. By the way, I heard you were there at the SS Anemone incident.
そういえば 君もあねもね号事件の被害者だそうだな
W-Why do you know that?!
何で そんなこと
君島コウは あねもね号事件のとき ほぼ同時刻に死亡している
Kimijima Kou died practically simultaneously with the SS Anemone incident.
もう一度 聞く
Let me ask you once more.
Are you familiar with the name of Kimijima Kou?
君島コウという名前に心当たりは？
No.
いえ
そうか
I see.
Misa
Misa?!
ミサ姉
Misa, hello? Hello?
ミサ姉 もしもし ミサ姉
You mustn't give the Kimijima Reports to anyone.
君島レポートを人に渡しては駄目
全て あなたが守り通して…
You must protect everything.
ミサ姉
Misa?
You...
あなたが…
Call ended
Sister
Group 1
Address book
Phone Number
Email
Kai
Kai's House
Dad
Mom
Robot Clinic
Home
Mizuka
Kamada Motors
Minato Motors
Sister
お姉ちゃん 瑞榎姉 いなくなっちゃったよ
Sis...
Mizuka died...
ロボ部も…
The Robotics Club too...
お姉ちゃん 何で
Sis... why?
Sister
Sis?!
お姉ちゃん つ… 通話
Pick up!
もしもし もしもし お姉ちゃん
Hello? Hello, Sis?
Aki...
アキ
お姉ちゃん
Sis...
Are you okay?
元気にしてた？
うん お姉ちゃんは？
Yeah! And you?
特に変わったことはないわ
Nothing has changed really.
By the way, what's going on with the GunPro-1?
それより ガンつくはどうなっているの
えっ… うん…
万博に出すんでしょ メール見たわよ
I heard you're entering the Expo with it! I read your mail!
Well, I...
それが…
やっぱり 駄目だったのね
So you couldn't do it.
だから 言ったのに
I told you.
アキは平凡止まりだって
You're ordinary.
私の夢をかなえるのは 無理よ
Fulfill my dream?
Impossible!
ミサ姉の夢？
You had a dream about Misa?
Yeah.
Doesn't he look like he's crying?
この子 泣いてるように見えない？
Dunno...
さあ
Aki?
アキちゃん
カイ 聞いててくれないかな
Kai, will you listen?
Sure...
中央種子島高校 ロボット研究部は 本日をもって解散します
The Central Tanegashima High School Robotics Research Club is disbanded as of today!
皆さまのご愛顧 ありがとうございました
Thank you for your kind cooperation!
えっと
Uh...
で？
So?
後は うちだけで何とかするつもり
I'll handle the rest.
何とかって
What rest?
ロボ部はなくなっちゃったわけだから
The club is gone, so I'll do it myself.
後は うち 個人で何とかする
諦めてないってわけだ
So you haven't given up?
それが許されると思ってるわけ？
Do you think they'll let you?
許されるわけないと思う
No. The principal will get really angry.
教頭先生 怒ると思う
ううん ジュンや昴 昴のお父さんだって怒るに決まってる
Jun and Subaru... Subaru's father too.
瑞榎姉が亡くなったばかりなのに
I know it goes against common sense since Mizuka just died.
非常識だっていうのも分かってるつもり
それでも諦めないっていうの
Yet still you won't give up?
I want to catch up to my sister!
お姉ちゃんに追い付きたいの
うちは お姉ちゃんと違って平凡だよ
Unlike her, I'm ordinary.
But I can't let this go! Anything but this!
でも どうしても譲れない
これだけは譲れないの
Kai... what do you say?
カイ カイはどう思う
許せないね
I won't approve.
Kai...
カイ
Mizuka died.
瑞榎さんが亡くなったんだよ 昴が大ケガしてるんだよ
Subaru's hospitalized.
万博なんて言ってる場合じゃない
And you still go on about the Expo?
アキちゃん個人だからいいって話じゃない
And you really think it'll be fine if you do it by yourself?
We all built the GunPro-2 together!
だいたい ガンつく２はみんなで造ったロボだろ
How can you think it's okay to just do what you want?
そんな わがままが通用すると思ってるの
分かってる
I get it.
You don't.
分かってない
分かってるよ
I do!
カイ
Kai?
I'm going to the principal to tell her to get it taken apart right away.
教頭の所に行って すぐ解体してもらうよう言ってくる
But...
そんな
待って カイ
Wait, Kai!
待って 待ってよ
Wait! Wait!
Please!
お願い これは うちの最後の希望なの
This is my last hope!
みんなとの絆なの お姉ちゃんとの絆なの
My bond with you guys! With my sister!
Please...
だから お願い
それは 俺への頼みと受け取っていいわけ？
Should I consider that a request of me?
じゃ 勝負しなよ
In that case, fight me.
勝負だよ 『キルバラ』の
Fight me in Kill-Ballad.
Kai...
カイ
やるの やらないの
Fight or not?
I can't win...
勝てるわけないじゃん
譲れないんじゃなかったの
I thought you wouldn't give up on your dream.
Show me how serious you are.
アキちゃんの ホントの本気ってやつを見せてよ
Stupid.
バカ
What's wrong, Aki the Turtle?
どうしたの スッポンアキちゃん
Stupid!
バカ
無駄に前向きなんじゃないの
I thought you were insanely optimistic?
You idiot!
カイの バカー
それで終わり？
It's over!
I wanna catch up to my sister!
うちは お姉ちゃんに追い付きたいの
平凡止まりだって言って ロボットのことがらくただって言って
She called me ordinary! She called robots junk!
そんな お姉ちゃんに追い付いて
I wanna catch up and...
うちを うちを うちを
And...
Huh?
勝負あったね
We fought.
Huh? Did I just...
い… 今の うちが？
うん アキちゃんの勝ち
Yeah. You win.
But... Why? You...
カイ どうして 今…
あめちゃん ある？
Got some candy?
うん ある
Yeah.
ありがと 今度 返すよ
Thanks. I'll get you some later.
負けた以上 最後まで付き合うよ
I lost, so I'll tag along.
東京でも 万博でも
Tokyo and the Expo too.
また ２人だけになっちゃったね
It's just the two of us again...
どっちにしろ 万博には俺たちしか行けそうになかったから
We were the only ones who could get to the Expo anyway,
so it's not a big difference.
変わりないさ
がきが 盛ってんじゃねえぞ
You're kids, not rabbits!
ド ドク
Doc?
ま まさか ドクがロボットの解体に
You came to take it apart?
ああ そういう発注が来たんでな
Yeah, I got told to do that.
だが 気が変わった
But I changed my mind.
俺の趣味で ここに寝てる２体のロボを直してみようと思うんだが
It's my hobby, so I'm thinking of fixing these two robots.
お前ら 付き合う気はあるか
Would you wanna tag along?
ドク
Doc!
こら 何してる
What're you doing?!
Mitchie?
ミッチー
Don't you get into talks without me there!
先生抜きで勝手に話を進めるんじゃない
Sorry, Mitchie, but we're not giving up!
悪いけど ミッチー うちらは諦めないからね
We're fixing GunPro-2 and taking it to the Expo!
ガンつく２を直して 万博に出るんだから
That's how we roll, Mitsuhiko.
そういうことだ 充彦
よかったぁ
Thank God! I thought Doc was gonna take it apart.
先生 ドクがロボを解体するんじゃないかって早とちりしちまったぞ
ほれ 瀬乃宮
Here!
Mitchie, what...
ミッチー これ どうしたの
Did you turn into a criminal or something?
犯罪にでも 手 染めた？
Stupid! I got it back from the school!
バカ 学校から取り返してきたんだよ
取り返したって
Back?
お前ら 去年のＲＯＢＯ－ＯＮＥで準優勝しただろうが
You got second place in the Robo-One last year!
あのときの賞金だ
It's the prize from then.
こいつがありゃ 資金の足しになるだろう
This should boost your funds a little.
Mitchie...
ミッチー
But why?
でも どうして
ここでロボ部が終わっちまったら 伊禮に怒られそうだからな
Irei would get mad at me if the club ended here.
やるじゃねえか
Not half bad.
What if the principal finds out?
教頭にバレたら ヤバいんじゃない？
We'll figure that out when the time comes.
そんときは そんときだ
カイ
Kai...
Let's go to the Expo!
行こう 万博に お姉ちゃんのいる東京に
To Tokyo where my sister is!
Sure.
全て 守り通して…
Protect everything.
ゲジ姉
Sister Centipede!
Yes?
はい
君島レポート ナンバー７をダウンロードしてよ
Download Kimijima Report No. 7.
Are you sure?
よろしいのですか
うん
はっきりさせときたいんだ 東京に行く前に
I want to find everything out before we go to Tokyo.
Understood. Downloading Kimijima Report No. 7.
了解しました 君島レポート ナンバー７ ダウンロードを開始します
何だ おい ゲジ姉
Huh?
Sister Centipede, there's no report... What's going on?
レポートが出てこないけど どうなってるんだ
It seems that Kimijima Report No. 7 is not a text file.
君島レポート ナンバー７に レポート本文は存在しないようです
存在しないって…
No text?!
君島レポート ナンバー７ 起動完了
Kimijima Report No. 7 has been executed.
The six Kimijima Reports have been distributed throughout the world using Iru-O.
６つの君島レポートは『居ル夫。』を通じ 全世界へと拡散されました
拡散って どういうことだよ
Distributed? What do you mean?!
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
Showing the outline of a lively scene
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
取り上げる思いが
描いた空
柔らかな風が吹き
The wind blows gently stroking
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Triple Axel
Impacttt!!
You even changed the move's name.
Tune in next week too!